So in this video, we are going to create value blocks and we will start value block creation on block
61, which is in Sector 15.
Over here you can see it.
So let's just create a value block on Block 61.
We have to type 61 and let's just do data read first.
So over here, you can see there are zeros in this block.
So let's just create this block in value block.
So to create value block, what you have to do is you have to press these four buttons in sequence,
right?
The first four buttons.
So first you have to do request, then interpolation, then select and then authenticate.
So you will see authentication success message over here.
Right after that, what you have to do is you can either create value block or you can read data as
you were doing before.
So let's just create value.
Block value, right?
So we will create value.
Block Starting with 100.
And we will do well, right?
And you can see value, right value, success.
So let's just read value.
And the read value is 100.
So this is how you create value blocks.
Now let's just try to read this data in hexadecimal.
So we will do data read so it will read all the 16 bytes.
In this block.
So here you can see the 16 bytes.
So the first four bytes is our value, which we have written, which is in 100.
So these four bytes are dedicated to this value, right?
After that, the next four byte is the complement of the first four bytes.
These four bytes, the first four bytes, it's a complement, right?
So it's a complement of these first four bytes.
After that, after the complement, the first four bytes are again repeated over here.
So it's creating the backup over here as a backup.
So it's repeating the first four bytes over here as well.
Then last four bytes is the complement of the of this complement, right?
The middle four bytes.
So this is the structure of value block, which makes a classic follows, right?
So this is the standard way in which a classic card creates value.
Block.
And we cannot change this standard, right?
This is the way we program value blocks in classic card.
So now what we will do is we will do again request and anti-collision then select and then authenticate,
and then we will do value read one more time.
And we can perform increment and decrement operations as well.
So let's just do increment operation and we will do increment increase by 30.
So let's just do it.
And you can see value increase success.
And then and let's just read this value one more time.
To the next value after the increment.
We got 130 plus 100 plus 30 is 130.
Right.
So this is 130.
Over here, the correct value.
Let's just do one more increment of.
Then.
Right.
So the value read will show.
140.
Right.
So it's showing the correct value.
Now we can do decrement operations in a similar manner.
So what you have to do is you have to provide.
The number which you want to decrement.
Let's suppose we want to decrement 25 and we type value 25 over here.
And let's just do decrease.
Value, decreased success.
And let's just do value read one more time.
So the new value is 115.
So this is how value blocks are created using this RC 522 software which we used with STM eight microcontroller.